dublinairport.com 2019-10-12

# Dublin Airport Privacy policy

At Dublin Airport, daa plc, in keeping with our commitment to be open with all passengers, customers, partners and employees, we have developed this Privacy Statement Overview, a quick and simple summary explaining how we manage, share and look after your information. 

Further details regarding specific areas such as Car Parks, Fast Track, Lounge Services or Platinum Services can be accessed in the Detailed Privacy Policy for  Dublin Airport Products and Services. 

We are determined to deliver a great welcome and a great service to all passengers, customers, and partners. To enable this, we need to collect a range of information about you, if you are a passenger - your name and flight details, or if you are a car park customer - your name, car registration and email address. This Privacy Statement covers people who may interact with us in the following ways: 

  * People that use products or services offered via daa and Dublin Airport websites, including The Loop Click and Collect, and Dublin Airport Car Parking
  * People that sign up to receive information from daa, Dublin Airport, Cork Airport and The Loop (e.g. newsletters)
  * People that send us feedback via our websites or social media channels
  * Visitors to our websites
  * User of our Dublin Airport app
  * Passengers and other visitors to daa-owned properties, Dublin Airport and Cork Airport.

If you have any general queries about your experience in dealing with us, please contact [customerexperience@daa.ie](mailto:customerexperience@daa.ie).

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement, please contact our Data Protection Officer by email at [dataprotection@daa.ie](mailto:dataprotection@daa.ie) or in writing at:

Data Protection Officer,  
Cargo Building 6, Corballis Park,  
Dublin Airport.

We fully respect your right to privacy and undertake to only collect data as required to deliver the services you need, or with your clear permission and consent. In addition, we are required to implement statutory regulations in civil aviation as part of our role as an airport operator. The reasons for processing your data may include the following:

1\. Delivering the passenger experience – our job is to get you through your airport journey as smoothly and comfortably as possible. Due to the highly regulated nature of air travel, we are required to process data for safety and security reasons as described in detail below. 

2\. Providing additional services at the airport – we provide additional services which you may choose to use to enhance your journey. In providing these services to you, we may need to gather some data. For example, these services may require that we process payments, and keep your name and other details, such as car registration and email address; we may gather details of your travelling companions or special dietary needs to enable us to plan and deliver the relevant travel services. Additional services we deliver directly include:

2.1 Car parking services to provide you with access to the most convenient parking locations – click here for further details and our Car Parking Privacy Statement.

2.2 Fast Track services to save you time getting through Security Screening – click here for further details and our Fast Track Privacy Statement.

2.3 Lounge services to help you relax or do some work before you fly – click here for further details and our Lounge Privacy Statement. 

2.4 Airport Club services – membership provides convenience and unlimited access to services such as Airport Parking Security Fast Track, and Lounges in both Terminals 1 and 2 – click here for further details and our Airport Club Privacy Statement. 

2.5 Platinum Services – our suite of travel services to optimise your journey includes premium departures and arrivals facilities, private check in, dedicated Security Screening, suites and chauffeur-driven escort to your plane – click here for further details and our Platinum Services Privacy Statement. 

2.6 The Loop Retail Services – Duty Free – for in-store purchases, we do not collect personal data (we do not retain payment data in our shops). However, in order to provide duty free prices, we collect flight details as provided on your boarding card. The information collected is limited to the item purchased and flight information such as the airline and destination details. See here for the [Opens in new windowloop.ie](http://theloop.ie/) and see here for Privacy Statement details.

2.7 The Loop Retail Services – ‘Click & Collect’ – we offer a ‘Click & Collect’ service that requires us to collect information to enable us to identify you at the point of collection and to communicate with you if you ask us to – see here for the loop.ie and see here for Privacy Statement details. 

3.  Providing free wi-fi while you use our airports – under Irish law, all ‘Internet Service Providers’ or ISPs are obliged to maintain records of internet access for a period of 12 months. As we do not collect your name as part of the wi-fi sign-up, we store the IP address assigned to you and the MAC address of the device you used to access to wi-fi service. We keep these records as required by law.

4\. Protecting the welfare of passengers, visitors and staff at Dublin Airport – we may need to record personal details relating to any iduals involved in incidents or accidents in the airport or its environs.

5\. We may also perform statistical analysis on passenger and customer flows to improve our services and plan for future enhancements to our airport facilities – in this situation, we will anonymise your data before any analysis is performed so we cannot identify you.

6\. Ensuring the safety and security of civil aviation – this includes CCTV and Queue Measurement: 

6.1 Safety and Security – Closed Circuit Television (CCTV) – as the operator of Dublin Airport and Cork Airport, daa are obliged to keep the airports and their environs safe and secure. To assist us in this, we operate CCTV security systems both landside and airside and our Airport Police manage these important security controls. CCTV images of you are considered to be personal data and we carefully safeguard access to these images. We retain all CCTV footage for 30 days.

6.2 Safety and Security – Queue Measurement – we are also obliged by statutory regulations in civil aviation to measure how long it takes to get you safely through the security screening process. We do this by monitoring passengers’ mobile devices while they move through the screening area. We only access the MAC address of your wi-fi or Bluetooth interface, and purge this data after six (6) years. You are free to switch off your wi-fi or Bluetooth as you go through security or the airport generally if you wish.

6.3 If you use the automatic border controls such as passport e-readers, you may be required to provide personal data. This system is controlled by Irish Naturalisation & Immigration Service (INIS) for the purpose of border control.

6.4 If purchasing goods from the retail outlets post US Preclearance, officially known as US Customs & Border Patrol (USCBP), your passport may be requested to verify your age and residency status. We are required to collect this data under the terms of the treaty to implement USCBP agreed between Ireland and the USA.

6.5 If travelling to the USA, you may have been asked to provide some personal information in advance. You may be asked to provide additional details at US Preclearance, officially known as US Customs & Border Patrol (USCBP). This information is collected by USCBP and daa has no access to this data. Click here for additional information on US Customs & Border Patrol.

We may also need to share your data with partners such as your airline or their ground handler, to help get you to your destination. 

Where this data is provided by us to the third party to deliver a service to you, the processing is covered by this Privacy Statement. Where you provide your data directly to a third party, we have no involvement in that transaction or access to the data and the processing is the responsibility of the third party. An example of this would be going online to rent a car for collection at the airport.

Where data is provided by us to a regulatory body or law enforcement agency to meet statutory or regulatory obligations, activities undertaken by those parties is outside our control and hence fall outside of the scope of this Privacy Statement.

Agencies that we may be obliged to share information with include: 

  * An Garda Síochana (National Police Service) 
  * Garda National Immigration Bureau (GNIB) Irish Naturalisation and Immigration Service (INIS) 
  * Revenue – Irish Tax and Customs Service

The purpose of this statement is to let you know what to expect when daa plc (daa) collects personal information via Closed Circuit Television (CCTV) cameras located through the Dublin Airport campus. With this Privacy Statement, we want to provide transparency on how we treat personal data and the purposes for which we collect data. 

This Privacy Statement applies to people that visit the Dublin Airport campus. 

This Privacy Statement does not apply to CCTV data processing by third parties, such as airlines, handling agents, or retail tenants. daa has no access to data processing by third parties or to the data involved, unless otherwise stated, and cannot be held responsible for it. 

We operate CCTV cameras located through the Dublin Airport campus, including in terminal buildings and surrounding environs. Your personal data may be collected through the operation of these CCTV cameras. 

The purpose for collecting the personal information that you provide is to allow us to: 

  * Protect the safety of passengers and staff at Dublin Airport 
  * Prevent, detect, and respond to criminal activity 
  * Comply with our legal and regulatory obligations to safeguard and protect civil aviation 
  * Investigate safety and security incidents in response to reported incidents, complaints, claims, or regulatory / compliance audits or other issues. 

CCTV data may also be used to monitor passenger or vehicle flows or to conduct statistical analysis of those flows. This processing is carried out in daa’s legitimate interests and allows us to ensure we can continue to invest in the infrastructure to meet passengers’ future needs at Dublin Airport. This does not affect your rights as a data subject. See your rights in relation to your information below. 

We may be required to share your information to Comply with our legal and regulatory obligations Investigate safety incidents, security incidents or criminal activity. 

We may share personal data relating to you recorded on CCTV with: 

  * Competent authorities such as An Garda Síochana or the Irish Aviation Authority 
  * Third parties who operate retail outlets, or who provide services to passengers such as airlines or handling agents where we have a statutory obligation to do so. 

All personal data collected for the purposes specified in this statement is processed inside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA) and will never be transferred to countries located outside the EU or the EEA. 

We retain CCTV footage for thirty (30) days. Any CCTV footage identified as relevant to a formally reported incident is retained for six (6) years from the date of the reported incident. Where an investigation or claim arising from a reported incident take longer than 6 years to be processed, the CCTV footage identified as relevant to that incident may be retained for longer than 6 years. 

Your rights as a data subject are as follows: 

  1. Right of access – you have the right to find out if we hold any personal data relating to you. You also have the right to obtain a copy of any such personal data we hold on you. The request, referred to as a Data Access Request
  2. Right to rectification – you have the right to request we rectify any information we hold about you that is inaccurate.
  3. Right to erasure – you have the right to request we erase any information we hold on you, provided there is valid grounds for doing so.
  4. Right to restriction of processing – you have the right to request we temporarily restrict the processing of your personal data, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  5. Right to object – you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, namely in the case processing is carried out in the legitimate interests of daa.
  6. Right to lodge a complaint – if you are unhappy with how we have acted in handling your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority in your EEA country of residence, place of work, or with the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner in Ireland.

Any personal information that you provide to daa or its subsidiaries will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality and handled in accordance with Data Protection laws and the General Data Protection Regulation.

Security of your personal data is very important to us. We take all reasonable technical and organisational measures to prevent the loss, misuse, unauthorised access, disclosure, or alteration of your personal data. These measures include: 

  * We apply various levels of access control to restrict access to your personal information to daa employees and contractors who require a level of access as part of their role 
  * We work with experienced, specialised vendors to develop and maintain our platforms 
  * We regularly review and audit our security and data protection policies and procedures to ensure a high level of operational security is maintained

Under the Data Protection Act 2018 and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) you have the right to: 

  * Access your personal data by making a subject access request 
  * Rectification, erasure or restriction of your information where this is justified 
  * Object to the processing of your information where this is justified 
  * Data portability 
  * All you need to do is write to us and ask for it under the Data Protection Acts. We refer to these requests as Data Subject Rights Requests. Please download the PDF here for Data Subject Rights Request guidance. 

This Privacy Statement applies to all personal information collected by daa plc for the purposes specified below. The purpose of this statement is to let you know what to expect when daa collects personal information via our websites, telephone, e-mail, manual forms, or in person. 

With this Privacy Statement, we want to provide transparency on how we treat personal data and the purposes for which we collect data. 

This Privacy Statement applies to people that: 

  * Submit general customer queries 
  * Request assistance as a person with reduced mobility (PRM) 
  * Request an ‘Important Flyer’ wristband or lanyard 

This Privacy Statement does not apply to data processing by 3rd parties, such as airlines, handling agents, or retail tenants. daa has no access to data processing by 3rd parties or to the data involved, unless otherwise stated, and cannot be held responsible for it. 

We may collect information about you via this website, via telephone, e-mail, forms, or in person. We may will collect the following personal information from you: 

  * Name 
  * Email address 
  * Postal address 
  * Contact number 
  * Travel date 
  * GP note confirming Important Flyer’s diagnosis of autism or sensory issue 

We collect this information to enable us to process your request for assistance as a person with reduced mobility, an Important Flyer wristband or lanyard and effectively resolving your query. This information is only processed with your consent and we will never use this information for any other purposes than those specified above. 

We engage specialist service providers to assist us in delivering a high-quality passenger experience. As such, we may share the personal information we hold about you with the following types of organisations

  * PRM service providers

On occasion, we may be required to redirect your query to the appropriate airline, service provider, etc. We will always ask for your consent before disclosing this information.

All personal data collected for the purposes specified in this statement is processed inside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA) and will never be transferred to countries located outside the EU or the EEA. 

When you provide us with personal information, we delete this information in line with our data retention policy. We will retain the following personal data you have provided for the following time periods; 

  * Customer query information – three (3) years post query 
  * PRM requests – three (3) years post query 
  * Important Flyer request information – one (1) year post request 

We may collect a GP note confirming diagnosis of autism or sensory issue for the Important Flyer. This sensitive information is only processed with your consent and will only be used to verify eligibility for an Important Flyer wristband or lanyard. This data is not retained and is securely destroyed once verified. 

Your rights as a data subject are as follows: 

  1. Right of access – you have the right to find out if we hold any personal data relating to you. You also have the right to obtain a copy of any such personal data we hold on you. The request is referred to as a ‘Data Access Request’. 
  2. Right to rectification – you have the right to request we rectify any information we hold about you that is inaccurate. 
  3. Right to erasure – you have the right to request we erase any information we hold on you, provided there are valid grounds for doing so. 
  4. Right to restriction of processing – you have the right to request we temporarily restrict the processing of your personal data, provided there are valid grounds for doing so. 
  5. Right to data portability – you have the right to obtain a machine-readable copy of the information we hold on you, and have it transferred to another controller if required. 
  6. Right to object – you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, namely in the case processing is carried out in the legitimate interests of daa. 
  7. Right to lodge a complaint – if you are unhappy with how we have acted in handling your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority in your EEA country of residence, place of work, or with the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner in Ireland. 

### Contact Us

If you have any general queries about your experience in dealing with us, please contact [customerexperience@daa.ie](mailto:customerexperience@daa.ie).

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement, please contact our Data Protection Officer by email at [dataprotection@daa.ie](mailto:dataprotection@daa.ie) or in writing at:

Data Protection Officer,  
Cargo Building 6, Corballis Park,  
Dublin Airport.

If we wish to gather information to contact you, e.g. for marketing purposes, we will ask for your consent to do so in advance. If you have purchased products or services from us,  we'll use the information we collect when you make a purchase or use our services to choose content we think will interest you. We may offer you reminders or information to assist us in delivering those services unless you have asked us not to contact you in relation to products or services purchased. If you have provided consent, you can unsubscribe at any time to remove that consent.

This Privacy Statement applies to individuals that have given their consent to avail of direct marketing communications from daa plc regarding promotions, products or services electronically via email, SMS and / or push notifications.

We would like to provide you with information about new products, promotions, special offers, services and other information that we feel you may be interested in. As part of a purchase on our digital channels, we offer you the opportunity to opt in to our marketing communications.

You will always be given the opportunity to withdraw that consent on every electronic communication you receive from daa plc by unsubscribing at any time.

When you sign up to marketing communications, we’ll normally contact you by email, but we may also send you marketing texts if you have given us your mobile number for this purpose.

This Privacy Statement applies to all personal information collected by daa plc for the purposes specified below. The purpose of this statement is to let you know what to expect when daa collects personal information about you via our websites, telephone, email, mobile devices, manual forms, or in person.

With this Privacy Statement, we want to provide transparency on how we treat personal data and the purposes for which we collect data.

This Privacy Statement applies to individuals that:

  * Avail of any of the following daa products/services; 
    * Car Parks
    * Fast Track
    * Executive Lounges
  * Sign up to receive information such as newsletters and offers
  * Visit our website or use one of our apps
  * Visit one of our airports.

We may collect information about you via this website, telephone, email, mobile device, form, or in person. We may collect the following personal information from you;

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Contact number
  * Vehicle registration
  * Credit card information
  * Audio recordings from barriers/pay machines.

We collect this information about you to enable us to provide the product / service you have requested. Your personal data is processed for the performance of the contract between daa, as data controller, and you, the data subject.

Where we give you the option of providing additional personal details, we ask for your consent. If you do not wish us to process this information any further, you can withdraw consent at any time by contacting the relevant customer service team.

Information you provide may also be used to conduct statistical analysis of our products / services, analyse future trends and build customer profiles. This processing is carried out in daa’s legitimate interests and allows us to ensure customers continue to find our products valuable and so that we can continue to invest in the infrastructure to meet customers’ future needs at Dublin Airport. This does not affect your rights as a data subject. See your rights in relation to your information for more. 

At times, we engage third parties to assist us in providing our products / services. Your personal data may occasionally be shared with these organisations to allow us to provide you with the product / service you have requested. daa will never share your information with these organisations for marketing purposes.

In this respect, we may share your data with the following types of organisations:

  * Software providers
  * Vehicle breakdown assistance providers
  * Coach service providers
  * Car valet providers
  * Lounge operators
  * Payment processors.

We engage a specialised software provider (Advam) located in Australia to develop, host, and maintain our booking engine. As a result, when you make a Car Park, Fast Track, or Executive Lounge booking online, your personal data will be transferred outside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA).

We work hard to ensure your personal data is always kept secure and safeguards are in place to secure your personal data when transferred outside the EU or the EEA. daa have contractual agreements in place with our software provider to ensure a high standard of security is maintained when processing your personal data.

When you provide us with personal information, we delete this information in line with our data retention policy. We will retain the following personal data you have provided for the following time periods;

  * Booking information – we retain your name, email address, contact number, and vehicle registration for six (6) years post the last booking
  * Credit card information – we only store a hash of your card number for identification purposes. A ‘hash’ is a secure representation of your card number that can be used to identify your card but cannot be used to recreate your card number. We retain the card number hash for six (6) years post the last transaction.
  * We do not retain full card details unless you have consented to us doing so
  * Audio recordings – we keep audio recordings of conversations at the car park barrier for a period of 30 days.

We will not collect any sensitive information / special categories of personal data relating to you for the purposes outlined in this statement.

Your rights as a data subject are as follows:

  1. Right of access – you have the right to find out if we hold any personal data relating to you. You also have the right to obtain a copy of any such personal data we hold on you. The request is referred to as a Data Access Request.
  2. Right to rectification – you have the right to request we rectify any information we hold about you that is inaccurate.
  3. Right to erasure – you have the right to request we erase any information we hold on you, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  4. Right to restriction of processing – you have the right to request we temporarily restrict the processing of your personal data, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  5. Right to data portability – you have the right to obtain a machine-readable copy of the information we hold on you, and have it transferred to another controller if required.
  6. Right to object – you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, namely in the case processing is carried out in the legitimate interests of daa.
  7. Right to lodge a complaint – if you are unhappy with how we have acted in handling your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority in your EEA country of residence, place of work, or with the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner in Ireland.

### Contact us

If you wish to get more information on this Privacy Policy, please contact:

  * Email Car Parks: [parkingdublin@dublinairport.com](mailto:parkingdublin@dublinairport.com)
  * Email Fast Track: [fasttrack@dublinairport.com](mailto:fasttrack@dublinairport.com)
  * Or write to us at:

Car Parks Admin / Fast Track  
Dublin Airport  
Co Dublin, Ireland

This Privacy Statement applies to all personal information collected by daa plc for the purposes specified below. The purpose of this statement is to let you know what to expect when daa collects personal information about you via our websites, telephone, email, manual forms, or in person.

With this Privacy Statement, we want to provide transparency on how we treat personal data and the purposes for which we collect data.

This Privacy Statement applies to individuals that:

  * Register with Airport Club
  * Sign up to receive information such as newsletters and offers.

We may collect information about you via this website, telephone, email, forms, or in person We may collect the following personal information from you;

  * Name
  * Postal address
  * Car registration
  * Email address
  * Contact number
  * Vehicle registration
  * Credit card information.

We collect this information about you to enable us to process your Airport Club membership. Your personal data is processed in this respect for the performance of the contract between daa, as data controller, and you, the data subject.

Where we give you the option of providing additional personal details, we ask for your consent. If you do not wish us to process this information any further, you can withdraw consent at any time by contacting the relevant customer service team.

Information you provide may also be used to conduct statistical analysis of our products / services, analyse future trends, and build customer profiles. This processing is carried out in daa’s legitimate interests and allows us to ensure customers continue to find our products valuable and so that we can continue to invest in the infrastructure to meet customers’ future needs at Dublin Airport. This does not affect your rights as a data subject. See your rights in relation to your information for more.

At times, we engage third parties to assist us in providing our products/services. Your personal data may occasionally be shared with these organisations to allow us to provide you with the product / service you have requested. daa will never share your information with these organisations for marketing purposes.

In this respect, we may share your data with the following types of organisations:

  * Software providers
  * Lounge operators
  * Payment processors
  * Car park operators.

All personal data collected for the purposes specified in this statement is processed inside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA) and will never be transferred to countries located outside the EU or the EEA.

When you provide us with personal information, we delete this information in line with our data retention policy. We will retain the following personal data you have provided for the following time periods:

  * We retain your information for six (6) years after we finish supplying any services
  * Credit card information – we only store a hash of your card number for identification purposes. A ‘hash’ is a secure representation of your card number that can be used to identify your card but cannot be used to recreate your card number. We retain the card number hash for six (6) years post the last transaction.

We will not collect any sensitive information / special categories of personal data relating to you for the purposes outlined in this statement.

Your rights as a data subject are as follows:

  1. Right of access – you have the right to find out if we hold any personal data relating to you. You also have the right to obtain a copy of any such personal data we hold on you. The request is referred to as a Data Access Request.
  2. Right to rectification – you have the right to request we rectify any information we hold about you that is inaccurate.
  3. Right to erasure – you have the right to request we erase any information we hold on you, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  4. Right to restriction of processing – you have the right to request we temporarily restrict the processing of your personal data, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  5. Right to data portability – you have the right to obtain a machine-readable copy of the information we hold on you, and have it transferred to another controller if required.
  6. Right to object – you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, namely in the case processing is carried out in the legitimate interests of daa.
  7. Right to lodge a complaint – if you are unhappy with how we have acted in handling your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority in your EEA country of residence, place of work, or with the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner in Ireland.

### Contact us

If you wish to get more information on Airport Club Privacy Policy, please contact:

Airport Club  
Dublin Airport  
Co Dublin, Ireland  
Email: [airportclub@dublinairport.com](mailto:airportclub@dublinairport.com)

This Privacy Statement applies to all personal information collected by daa plc for the purposes specified below. The purpose of this statement is to let you know what to expect when daa collects personal information about you via our websites, telephone, email, mobile devices, manual forms or in person.

With this Privacy Statement, we want to provide transparency on how we treat personal data and the purposes for which we collect data.

This Privacy Statement applies to individuals that:

  * Use Dublin Airport Platinum Services
  * Make bookings for Dublin Airport Platinum Services.

We may collect information about you via this website, telephone, email, mobile devices, forms, or in person We may collect the following personal information from you;

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Contact number
  * Passport details
  * Travel details
  * Vehicle registration (if car parking requested)
  * Credit card information.

We collect this information about you to enable us to provide Platinum Services. Your personal data is processed for the performance of the contract between daa plc, as data controller, and you, the data subject.

Where we give you the option of providing additional personal details, we ask for your consent. If you do not wish us to process this information any further, you can withdraw consent at any time by contacting the relevant customer service team.

Information you provide may also be used to conduct statistical analysis of our products / services, analyse future trends, and build customer profiles. This processing is carried out in daa’s legitimate interests and allows us to ensure customers continue to find our products valuable and so that we can continue to invest in the infrastructure to meet customers’ future needs at Dublin Airport. This does not affect your rights as a data subject. See your rights in relation to your information for more.

At times, we engage third parties to assist us in providing our products/services. Your personal data may occasionally be shared with these organisations to allow us to provide you with the product / service you have requested. daa will never share your information with these organisations for marketing purposes.

In this respect, we may share your data with the following types of organisations:

  * Software providers
  * Government authorities (including Customs and Immigration).

All personal data collected for the purposes specified in this statement is processed inside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA) and will never be transferred to countries located outside the EU or the EEA.

When you provide us with personal information, we delete this information in line with our data retention policy. We will retain the following personal data you have provided for the following time periods;

  * Booking information – we retain your name, email address, contact number, and other details of your booking for six (6) years post the last booking
  * Credit card information – we only store a hash of your card number for identification purposes. A ‘hash’ is a secure representation of your card number that can be used to identify your card but cannot be used to recreate your card number – we retain the card number hash for six (6) years post the last transaction.
  * We do not retain full card details unless you have consented to us doing so.

We will not collect any sensitive information / special categories of personal data relating to you for the purposes outlined in this statement.

Your rights as a data subject are as follows:

  1. Right of access – you have the right to find out if we hold any personal data relating to you. You also have the right to obtain a copy of any such personal data we hold on you. The request is referred to as aData Access Request.
  2. Right to rectification – you have the right to request we rectify any information we hold about you that is inaccurate.
  3. Right to erasure – you have the right to request we erase any information we hold on you, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  4. Right to restriction of processing – you have the right to request we temporarily restrict the processing of your personal data, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  5. Right to data portability – you have the right to obtain a machine-readable copy of the information we hold on you, and have it transferred to another controller if required.
  6. Right to object – you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, namely in the case processing is carried out in the legitimate interests of daa.
  7. Right to lodge a complaint – if you are unhappy with how we have acted in handling your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority in your EEA country of residence, place of work, or with the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner in Ireland.

### Contact us

If you wish to get more information on Platinum Services Privacy Policy, please contact:

Platinum Services  
Dublin Airport  
Co Dublin, Ireland  
Email: [platinumservices@dublinairport.com](mailto:platinumservices@dublinairport.com)

This Privacy Statement applies to all personal information collected by daa plc for the purposes specified below. The purpose of this statement is to let you know what to expect when daa collects personal information about you via our websites, telephone, email, mobile devices, manual forms, or in person.

With this Privacy Statement, we want to provide transparency on how we treat personal data and the purposes for which we collect data.

This Privacy Statement applies to individuals that:

  * Purchase goods at one of our stores or websites
  * Sign up to receive information such as newsletters and offers
  * Submit a query via email, phone, online form or postal correspondence
  * Visit our website or use one of our apps.

We may collect information about you via this website, telephone, email, mobile devices, forms, or in person. We may collect the following personal information from you:

  * Shop and Collect – for purchases made in store for collection at a later date from a collection point – we may collect your name, contact number, flight information and credit card details
  * Click and Collect – for purchases made online for collection from a collection point – we may collect your name, email address, contact number, and credit card details.

For in-store purchases we do not collect personal data (we do not retain payment data in our shops). However, in order to provide duty free prices, we collect flight details as provided on your boarding card. The information collected is limited to the item purchased and flight information such as the airline and destination details.

We collect this information about you to enable us to complete the transaction for the product you have purchased. Your personal data is processed in this respect for the performance of the contract between daa, as data controller, and you, the data subject.

Boarding Card information may be collected in order to provide duty free prices. We collect this information to comply with legal and regulatory obligations.

Passport information – your passport may be requested in retail outlets that are past US Preclearance, officially known as US Customs & Border Patrol (USCBP) to verify your age and residency status. As you have already passed US Customs at this point in your journey, you are subject to US requirements. We collect this data under the terms of the treaty to implement USCBP agreed between Ireland and the USA.

Competitions – we may collect information when you enter competitions we run in-store or via our social media channels. We process this information to select competition winners and fulfill delivery of any such prizes, in line with our competition [Opens in new windowterms and conditions](https://www.theloop.ie/t/TermsConditions). We will ask for your consent to collect this information.

Staff purchases – if you are a member of staff at Dublin Airport  and Cork Airport or its associated affiliates, we may also collect information such as your Airport ID number. This information is required to enable us to complete the transaction for the product you have purchased.  _We  _collect this data as part of the fulfillment of a sales contract with you as a person eligible for a discounted price.

Newsletter or direct marketing communications – where you have provided personal data not necessary for completing a transaction, such as signing up for a newsletter, we will ask for your consent before collecting this information. You can withdraw consent at any time by visiting our Marketing Communications Privacy Policy.

Information you provide may also be used to conduct statistical analysis of our products / services, analyse future trends and build customer profiles. This processing is carried out in daa’s legitimate interests and allows us to ensure customers continue to find our products valuable and so that we can continue to invest in the infrastructure to meet customers’ future needs at Dublin Airport and Cork Airport. This does not affect your rights as a data subject. See your rights in relation to your information for more.

At times, we engage third parties to assist us in providing our products / services. Your personal data may be shared with these organisations to allow us to provide you with the product/service you have requested.

We may share your data with the following types of organisations:

  * Software providers
  * Web designers
  * Payment processors.

We will never share your information with these organisations for marketing purposes.

All personal data collected for the purposes specified in this statement is processed inside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA) and will never be transferred to countries located outside the EU or the EEA.

When you provide us with personal information, we delete this information in line with our data retention policy. We will retain the following personal data you have provided for the following time periods

  * Transactional information on the websites or at the tills – six (6) years after transaction
  * We do not retain full card details unless you have consented to us doing so.

We will not collect any sensitive information / special categories of personal data relating to you for the purposes outlined in this statement.

Your rights as a data subject are as follows:

  1. Right of access – you have the right to find out if we hold any personal data relating to you. You also have the right to obtain a copy of any such personal data we hold on you. The request is referred to as a Data Access Request.
  2. Right to rectification – you have the right to request we rectify any information we hold about you that is inaccurate.
  3. Right to erasure – you have the right to request we erase any information we hold on you, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  4. Right to restriction of processing – you have the right to request we temporarily restrict the processing of your personal data, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  5. Right to data portability – you have the right to obtain a machine-readable copy of the information we hold on you, and have it transferred to another controller if required.
  6. Right to object – you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, namely in the case processing is carried out in the legitimate interests of daa.
  7. Right to lodge a complaint – if you are unhappy with how we have acted in handling your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority in your EEA country of residence, place of work, or with the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner in Ireland.

### Contact us

If you wish to get more information on The Loop Privacy Statement, please contact:

The Loop  
Customer Service Desk  
Terminal 1,  
Dublin Airport  
Co Dublin, Ireland  
Email: [customerservice@theloop.ie](mailto:customerservice@theloop.ie)

This Privacy Statement applies to all personal information collected for the North Runway Project. The purpose of this statement is to let you know what to expect when personal information is collected via our website, telephone, e-mail, online or manual forms, in person, or via public registries.

With this Privacy Statement, we want to provide transparency on how we treat personal data and the purposes for which we collect data.

This Privacy Statement applies to individuals that:

  * Sign up to receive information such as project updates
  * Provide us with feedback via email, letter or consultation form
  * Provide us with their contact details via email, over the phone, or in person
  * Visit our website
  * Own or live in dwellings eligible for mitigation measures
  * Where eligible, opt-in to one or more of the mitigation schemes associated with Dublin Airport or North Runway.

We collect information about you via our website, telephone, letter, e-mail, forms, or in person. We collect the following personal information from you:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Details of your concerns and queries.

We may also collect information about from public registers such as the Land Direct website which is maintained by the Property Registration Authority of Ireland. Information from this registry is obtained from a secure source, within the European Union. For more details see [Opens in new windowwww.landdirect.ie](http://www.landdirect.ie/).

We collect this information to enable us to determine your eligibility for mitigation schemes and related matters, and to comply with our legal obligations as per the planning permission for North Runway approved by Fingal County Council.

We may retain a record of communications between daa and you in relation to enquiries, mitigation schemes and other engagement you may have related to the North Runway project and other Dublin Airport operations or runway projects.  This processing is carried out in daa’s legitimate interests.

We may also contact you with North Runway project updates and other relevant information, and respond to any queries you submit, if you have consented to us doing so. You can withdraw your consent at any time by unsubscribing or contacting the North Runway team.

At times, we engage third parties to assist us in providing our products/services. Your personal data may occasionally be shared with these organisations to allow us to provide you with the service you have requested. daa will never share your information with these organisations for marketing purposes.  In this respect, we may share your data with the following types of organisations;

  * Software providers
  * Consultants and/or contractors (for those eligible for mitigation schemes).

All personal data collected for the purposes specified in this statement is processed inside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA) and will never be transferred to countries located outside the EU or the EEA.

When you provide us with personal information, we will retain the following personal data you have provided for the following time periods:

If you are not in a mitigation scheme when we collect your information, we will delete this information six years after the completion of North Runway.

If you are in a mitigation scheme when your information is collected, we are required to retain your information indefinitely to comply with North Runway’s Planning Permission conditions. These require daa to review the noise contours associated with the mitigation schemes every two years.

Your rights as a data subject are as follows:

  1. Right of access – you have the right to find out if we hold any personal data relating to you. You also have the right to obtain a copy of any such personal data we hold on you. The request is referred to as a Data Access Request.
  2. Right to rectification – you have the right to request we rectify any information we hold about you that is inaccurate.
  3. Right to erasure – you have the right to request we erase any information we hold on you, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  4. Right to restriction of processing – you have the right to request we temporarily restrict the processing of your personal data, provided there are valid grounds for doing so.
  5. Right to data portability – you have the right to obtain a machine-readable copy of the information we hold on you, and have it transferred to another controller if required.
  6. Right to object – you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, namely in the case processing is carried out in the legitimate interests of daa.
  7. Right to lodge a complaint – if you are unhappy with how we have acted in handling your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority in your EEA country of residence, place of work, or with the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner in Ireland.

### Contact us

If you wish to get more information on this the North Runway project or this Privacy Statement, please contact:  
E-mail: [northrunway@daa.ie](mailto:northrunway@daa.ie)  
Phone: 1 800 80 44 22

Our websites use cookies. Cookies are small text files which are created on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. They enable your web browser (such as Internet Explorer or Mozilla Firefox) to remember which pages on a website you have visited and can also allow you to set preferences on some sites. Your web browser then sends these cookies back to the website on each subsequent visit so that they can recognise you and remember things like user preferences.

You can use our websites with no loss of functionality if cookies are disabled in your web browser.

By using our website, you are consenting to our use of cookies. You may opt out of the use of cookies by following the guidance provided in the Cookies and Web Browsing Statement here.

Detailed Information about Cookies and How To Opt-Out of Cookies

### Web Browsing

Technical details in connection with visits to our websites are logged for statistical purposes only. No information is collected that could be used by daa plc to identify website visitors. The technical details logged are confined to the following:

  * the top-level domain name used (e.g. .ie, .com, .org, .net)
  * data which shows the traffic of visitors around this website (such as pages accessed, and documents downloaded)
  * the type of web browser used by the website visitor.

Some of the above information is used to create summary statistics, which allow us to measure the number of visitors to our sites, identify what pages are accessed most frequently and generally help us to increase the usability and accessibility of our sites. We do not release any information or statistics to third parties. By using our websites, you accept the practices described in this Privacy Statement.

### How we use cookies

Cookies are small text files a website will place on your hard drive to record your preferences on a site or help identify trends for statistical purposes.  
It is important to note that accepting cookies used on our sites does not give us access to any personal information.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies by default, but you can usually refuse cookies or selectively accept certain cookies by adjusting the preferences in your browser. You can find information on how to adjust your cookie preferences for popular browsers below.

### Functional

Content Management System - cookies are used as part of the software used to manage and update our website content. The information gathered is not retained and the cookie is deleted when the browser is closed.

### Performance

Analytics - cookies are used to collect information anonymously to help daa better understand and improve how people interact with our site - they do not record personal information. The cookies collect information including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

### Security

These cookies enable daa to provide important secure features and services. Without them, accessing secure online services like The Loop website and Car Parking booking would not be possible.

### Advertising Cookies

daa use advertising cookies to measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns and how we can improve them for you. The advertising cookies used by daa are anonymous and are not used to collect information which can identify the user.

The following cookies are used specifically on this website:

Cookie name| Expiry| Description  
---|---|---  
  
FGTServer

| 

1 day

| 

The value of the cookie encodes the server that traffic should be directed to.  
  
IDE

| 

1.5 years

| 

This is the cookie used to serve targeted advertisements across third party websites when you leave our website.  
  
_dc_gtm_UA-63215094-6

| 

10 minutes

| 

Tracking cookie for Google tag manager that allows daa to understand your activity on the website  
  
_ga

| 

2 years

| 

Google Analytics cookie to record a user’s session  
  
_gat_UA-63215094-6

| 

10 minutes

| 

Cookie is used to send requests to doubleclick.net for third party advertising  
  
_gid

| 

24 hours

| 

Google Analytics cookie for distinguishing users across demographics  
  
fr

| 

1 month

| 

Enables remarketing when site visitors use Facebook over encrypted ID  
  
lang

| 

Session

| 

Remembers the user's selected language version of a website  
  
cookieconsent_dismissed

| 

1 year

| 

Cookie set to determine if the user has agreed to site cookies banner and implied consent.  
  
sf_timezoneoffset

| 

Session

| 

The time zone difference between UTC and the user's local time, in minutes.  
  
1P_JAR

| 

1 week

| 

These cookies are used to gather website statistics, and track conversion rates.  
  
CONSENT

|  | 

Consent to cookie for Google Analytics which lets us understand how you use our website.  
  
NID

| 

1 year

| 

The NID cookie contains a unique ID that remembers your preferences and other information, such as your preferred language  
  
_gali

| 

1 day

| 

This first party Google Analytics cookie is used by Google Analytics to specify user's country.  
  
__atuvc

| 

13 months

| 

Usage cookie to track addthis.com social sharing service  
  
__atuvs

| 

Session

| 

Usage cookie to track addthis.com social sharing service  
  
uid

| 

1 year

| 

Usage cookie to track addthis.com social sharing service  
  
uvc

| 

13 months

| 

Usage cookie to track addthis.com social sharing service  
  
vc

| 

1 year

| 

Usage cookie to track addthis.com social sharing service  
  
bt2

| 

255 days

| 

Usage cookie to track addthis.com social sharing service  
  
di2

| 

255 days

| 

Usage cookie to track addthis.com social sharing service  
  
loc

| 

13 months

| 

Usage cookie to track addthis.com social sharing service  
  
### How to delete or set cookie options in browsers

Should you wish to you can delete or block the use of cookies in your browser settings. However, once you do this, some features of our websites may not work as intended.

You can delete the cookies stored on your device or alternatively you can change your privacy settings on your browser via the following links:

### Microsoft Internet Explorer

  * Open the 'Tools' menu
  * Select 'Internet Options'
  * Open the 'Security' tab
  * Choose the 'Internet' zone
  * Identify the security level 'High' for this zone
  * Click 'OK'.

### Google Chrome

  * Open the 'Menu' (icon) on the toolbar
  * Choose 'Settings'
  * Open 'Advanced Settings'
  * Go to the 'Privacy' section and click on 'Content Settings'
  * In the 'Cookies' section, you can choose how cookies are used when you browse using Chrome.

### Mozilla Firefox

  * Open the 'Edit' menu
  * Choose 'Preferences'
  * Open 'Privacy & Security'
  * Choose 'Cookies'.

We review our Privacy Statements on a regular basis, and any updates will be highlighted in the version date below.

This Privacy Statement was last updated on: 25 May 2018 and is effective from 25 May 2018.

If you have any general queries about your experience in dealing with us, please contact [customerexperience@daa.ie](mailto:customerexperience@daa.ie).

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement, please contact our Data Protection Officer by email [dataprotection@daa.ie](mailto:dataprotection@daa.ie) or in writing at: 

Data Protection Officer,  
Cargo Building 6, Corballis Park,  
Dublin Airport.

### Sign Up to our Newsletter

Do you love Airport News, Offers and Discounts? 

  * Be the first to get airport promotions and offers
  * Enjoy great discounts
  * Receive airport news and updates

  * Be the first to get airport promotions and offers
  * Enjoy great discounts
  * Receive airport news and updates

Scan QR code with the WeChat app to visit **Dublin Airport WeChat**

Cookies are used to collect information anonymously. If you continue to use this site without changing your browser settings, you agree to their use. Please see our Privacy Policy.
